Guide to the Cecily Brownstone Papers MSS.134
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Author Files
  - Tharp, Edgar and Robert Jaycoxe, undated (Box 4, Folder 811)
  - Thompson, Lynne, undated (Box 4, Folder 812)
  - Thompson, Sylvia, undated (Box 4, Folder 813)
  - Thorne, Matt and John, undated (Box 4, Folder 814)
  - Thornton, Don, undated (Box 4, Folder 815)
  - Time-Life Books, undated (Box 4, Folder 816)
  - Tobias, Buddy, undated (Box 4, Folder 817)
  - Toklas, Alice, undated (Box 4, Folder 818)
  - Tolson, Berneita and Edith McCaig, undated (Box 4, Folder 819)
  - Toole, Joan, undated (Box 4, Folder 820)
  - Toupin, Elizabeth and Suzanne Rogers, undated (Box 4, Folder 821)
  - Tracy, Lisa, undated (Box 4, Folder 822)
  - Tracy, Marian, undated (Box 4, Folder 823)
  - Traub, Marvin, undated (Box 4, Folder 824)
  - Traux, Carol, undated (Box 4, Folder 825)
  - Tuttle, Audye, undated (Box 4, Folder 826)
  - Twinings of London, undated (Box 4, Folder 827)
  - Ukers, William, undated (Box 4, Folder 828)
  - Unity School of Christianity, undated (Box 4, Folder 829)
  - Urvater, Michèle, undated (Box 4, Folder 830)
  - Utility Club of Griffin, undated (Box 4, Folder 831)
  - Valldejuli, Carmen, undated (Box 4, Folder 832)
  - van der Post, Laurens, undated (Box 4, Folder 833)
  - van der Tuuk, Marianne, undated (Box 4, Folder 834)
  - van Lieu, Kris, undated (Box 4, Folder 835)
  - van Winter, Maria, undated (Box 4, Folder 836)
  - Vegetarian Times, editors of-, undated (Box 4, Folder 837)
  - Vehling, Joseph, undated (Box 4, Folder 838)
  - Vickers, Lois, undated (Box 4, Folder 839)
  - Villas, James, undated (Box 4, Folder 840)
  - Vita Mix Corporation, undated (Box 4, Folder 841)
  - Voltz, Jeanne, undated (Box 4, Folder 842)
  - von Welanetz, Diana and Paul -- See Welanetz, 1940-2002
  - Voth, Norma, undated (Box 4, Folder 843)
  - Wade, Charles, undated (Box 4, Folder 844)
  - Walden, Hilary, undated (Box 4, Folder 845)
  - Waldo, Myra, undated (Box 4, Folder 846)
  - Wang, Dee, undated (Box 4, Folder 847)
  - Ward, Artemas, undated (Box 4, Folder 848)
  - Warder, Marge, undated (Box 4, Folder 849)
  - Warner, Donna et al, undated (Box 4, Folder 850)
  - Washington, Martha, undated (Box 4, Folder 851)
  - Wason, Betty, undated (Box 4, Folder 852)
  - Wasserman, Debra, undated (Box 4, Folder 853)
  - Waugh, Alec, undated (Box 4, Folder 854)
  - Waxman, Nahum, undated (Box 4, Folder 855)
  - Weatherford, Jack, undated (Box 4, Folder 856)
  - Wechsberg, Joseph, undated (Box 4, Folder 857)
  - Wegener, Maj-Greth, undated (Box 4, Folder 858)
  - Weigley, Emma, undated (Box 4, Folder 859)
  - Weisel, Mindy, undated (Box 4, Folder 860)
  - Weiss, Edward, undated (Box 4, Folder 861)
  - Wejman, Jacqueline and Charles St. Peter, undated (Box 4, Folder 862)
  - Welanetz, Diana and Paul, undated (Box 4, Folder 863)
  - Welch, Adrienne and Mary Goodbody, undated (Box 4, Folder 864)
  - Welsh, Marie, undated (Box 4, Folder 865)
  - West, Ruth, undated (Box 4, Folder 866)
  - Weston, Edward, undated (Box 4, Folder 867)
  - Wheaton, Barbara, undated (Box 4, Folder 868)
  - Wheeler, Clementene, undated (Box 4, Folder 869)
  - White, Grace, undated (Box 4, Folder 870)
  - White, Merry, undated (Box 4, Folder 871)
  - White, Poppy, undated (Box 4, Folder 872)
  - Whitehead, Jessup, undated (Box 4, Folder 873)
  - Whitney, A.D.T., undated (Box 4, Folder 874)
  - Whyte, Karen, undated (Box 4, Folder 875)
  - Willand, Lois, undated (Box 4, Folder 876)
  - Williams, Elizabeth, undated (Box 4, Folder 877)
  - Williams, Sallie, undated (Box 4, Folder 878)
  - Williams-Heller, Anne, undated (Box 4, Folder 879)
  - Williamson, Cici and John Kelly, undated (Box 4, Folder 880)
  - Wilson, Adrian, undated (Box 4, Folder 881)
  - Wilson, Anne, undated (Box 4, Folder 882)
  - Wilson, Edward, undated (Box 4, Folder 883)
  - Wilson, Jacque, undated (Box 4, Folder 884)
  - Wine Advisory Board, undated (Box 4, Folder 885)
  - Winter, Patricia, undated (Box 4, Folder 886)
  - Withim, Gloria, undated (Box 4, Folder 887)
  - Witty, Helen, undated (Box 4, Folder 888)
  - Wolf, Burton, undated (Box 4, Folder 889)
  - Wood, Rebecca, undated (Box 4, Folder 890)
  - Woodier, Olwen, undated (Box 4, Folder 891)
  - Woodward, Nancy, undated (Box 4, Folder 892)
  - Wright, Richardson, undated (Box 4, Folder 893)
  - Wu, Sylvia, undated (Box 4, Folder 894)
  - Yates, Francesca, undated (Box 4, Folder 895)
  - Zelayeta, Elena, undated (Box 4, Folder 896)
  - Zeranska, Alina, undated (Box 4, Folder 897)
  - Unidentified Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 898)
  - Unidentified Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 899)
- Series II: Articles and Recipes
  Articles and recipes by Brownstone and others arranged chronologically.
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Brownstone's articles and recipes, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Recipes by others, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - General food-related articles by others, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - General food-related articles, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Recipes by ingredient, 1944-2000 (Box 46, Folder 9-33)
  - Works by Brownstone, 1924-1996 (Box 46, Folder 5-8, Box 48)
- Series III: Personal Files
  Personal files arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Art clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Biographical information, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Calendar, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Calendar, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Calendar, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Denmark trips, 1951, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - French Cooking for Little Girls, by Josy Ambroise-Thomas and edited by Cecily Brownstone, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets authored by Brownstone, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Publicity, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Quotation collection, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, passports, C.B. history, family records, NYU agreements, obituary, 1910-2005 (Box 47)
  - Rolodex, undated (Box 46, Folder 34-37)
  - C.B. annotated calendars, 1958, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 39)
  - Subseries A: Book Proposal Materials for Webster's Dictionary Cookbook
    Scope and Contents note
    Series III.A contains notes and correspondence on the subject of Webster's Dictionary Cookbook, a project on which Cecile Brownstone worked with her nephew, Jonathan Ned Katz. The material spans the period of 1985-1989, and its arrangment reflects Cecile's original categorization.
    - Final Cookbook Proposal, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Cookbook Proposal, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Cookbook (1 of 3), 1989 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Cookbook (2 of 3), 1989 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Cookbook (3 of 3), 1989 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Ambrosia, 1987-1989 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - American Heritage Cookbook, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - American Institute, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Ash Cake, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - A, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Axford, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - B, undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Brownstone, C., 1982-1983 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Boston Cream, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Cookery, undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - C, undated (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, Misc. (1 of 2), 1985-1989 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, Misc. (2 of 2), 1985-1989 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Collins-World, undated (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Computer Cookbook, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Copyright, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1986, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Craigie + Hulbert, undated (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Culinary Historians, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Design, Cookbook, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Dictionaries, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Dish CB = List, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Dish 1 = List, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Dish CB, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Dishes - List, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - E, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - "Food for Thought" Conference, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - F, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Hooker, undated (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - H, 1986, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - Influential Cookbooks, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - Jenkins, undated (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Larousse, undated (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Leonardi, undated (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Lowenstein Bibliography (Master), undated (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Lowenstein Bibliography, undated (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Lowenstein, undated (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - Marketing, undated (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Mathews, undated (Box 36, Folder 44)
    - Menues, undated (Box 36, Folder 45)
    - Merriam-Webster, 1984-1988 (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - N, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - NYU Library, 1981-1985 (Box 37, Folder 48)
    - P, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 49)
    - Notes, 1985-1989 (Box 37, Folder 50)
    - Pines, Chris, undated (Box 37, Folder 51)
    - Proposal (1 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 37, Folder 52)
    - Proposal (2 of 4), 1986-1987 (Box 37, Folder 53)
    - Proposal (3 of 4), 1986-1987 (Box 37, Folder 54)
    - Proposal (4 of 4), 1986, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 55)
    - Publishers, Cookbook, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 56)
    - Publishing, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 57)
    - Random House, 1967, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 58)
    - Research, 1986, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 59)
    - Sesame Noodles, undated (Box 37, Folder 60)
    - Simmons, A., undated (Box 37, Folder 61)
    - Sled + Ebbit, undated (Box 37, Folder 62)
    - Style, undated (Box 37, Folder 63)
    - Titles, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 64)
    - T, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 65)
    - W, undated (Box 37, Folder 66)
    - Transcript of Interview with Laura Shapiro, 2002-2004 (Box 37, Folder 67)
    - Sources, Dishes A-B, undated (Box 38)
    - Dishes C-Z, undated (Box 39)
- Series IV: Brownstone's Notes
  Brownstone's notes regarding The Pleasures of Cooking and individual cookbooks arranged alphabetically by title.
  - American Heritage Cookbook, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Cake Bible, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Comme Chez Soi, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cooking Craft, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - David, Elizabeth, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Elegant but Easy Cookbook, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The Everybody-Bring-a-Dish Cookbook, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Good Food and How to Cook It, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Good Food Without Meat, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Jim Lee's Chinese Cookbook, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Kentucky Housewife, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Kirmess Cook Book, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - L'art de Manger en Belgique, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Martha Washington's Rules for Cooking, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The New American Cuisine, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Paul Bocuse in Your Kitchen, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - The People's Republic of China Cookbook, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - The Pleasures of Cooking. Brownstone's recipe index by subject, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - The Pleasures of Cooking. Brownstone's recipe index by issue number, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The Pleasures of Cooking. Brownstone's recipe index by chef, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - The Pleasures of Cooking. Brownstone's recipe index by category, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - The Pleasures of Cooking. Brownstone's recipe index by country, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - The Pleasures of Cooking. Brownstone's other indexes, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The President's Cookbook, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - The Schwenkfelder Cook Book, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Two "Loaf-Givers", undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Woman's Day: The Only 25 Recipes You'll Ever Need, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Unidentified notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Series V: Manuscript Recipe Books
  Manuscript recipe books arranged alphabetically. The items in this series all require preservation work.
  - Chapman, Lora recipe book, 1873-1908 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Murrey, Thomas. The Welsh Rabbit Story, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Murrey, Thomas. The Welsh Rabbit Story (typescript), undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New Jersey Ms Cookbook, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Thompkins, Jane recipe book, [1928] (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified recipe book with recipe clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified German recipe book, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Photocopied Books
  Photocopied books arranged alphabetically.
  - Bakers Weekly Recipes, ca.1922 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Culinary Institute of America-Formulas of the Summer Refresher Course, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Makings of Eggnog, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Makings of Eggnog: A History with Recipes, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Eggnog: Its History, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Eggnog: A History of Eggnog, and a Collection of Recipes for Festive Occasions Around the Clock, and Round the Calendar, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - A History of Eggnog: And a Collection of Recipes for Festive Occasions, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Emery, Carla. Old Fashioned Recipe Book (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Emery, Carla. Old Fashioned Recipe Book (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Florida Cookery, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Frigidaire Recipes (loose pages, incomplete), undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Harris, H.G. and S.P. Borella All About Biscuits (1 of 2, with Brownstone's notes), undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Harris, H.G. and S.P. Borella All About Biscuits (2 of 2, With Brownstone's notes), undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Henderson, James. Meals by Fred Harvey: A Phenomenon of the American West, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Lucas, Dionne-Cooking School Packet, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The New Family Cook Book (four photocopied pages), 1891 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Oxford symposium (list of attendants and articles, 1 of 2), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Oxford symposium (list of attendants and articles, 2 of 2), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Practical Housekeeping (two photocopied pages), 1886 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Recipes of American and Other Iced Drinks, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Roth, Rodris. Tea Drinking in 18th-Century America: Its Etiquette and Equipage, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - The Rules of Civility (facsimile), undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Shoesmith, Thomas. The Biscuit Baker, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Shoesmith, Thomas. The Biscuit Baker's and Pastry-Cook's Assistant, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Troesch, Frances. Good Cooks of New England (American Women in Radio and Television), 1956 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Waldeck, Lewis and Mary. The Nero Wolfe Cookbook, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Wheeler, Nancy. Indian Recipes, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Yanner, Fred. The Modern Cake Baker, [1894] (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Series VII: Bibliographical Inventories
  - Alabama cookbooks, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Annotated inventory of cookbooks and pamphlets, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ellwanger, George. The Pleasures of the Table (photocopied bibliography), [1890] (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - English Language Cookbooks, 1600-1973-by author, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - English Language Cookbooks, 1600-1973-by subject, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - English Language Cookbooks, 1600-1973-by title (A - E), undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - English Language Cookbooks, 1600-1973-by title (F - M), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - English Language Cookbooks, 1600-1973-by title (N - Z), undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Gabbert, Betty. Cookbooks 'N Things, vol. III, no. 1, [1993] (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Gabbert, Betty. Cookbooks 'N Things, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Gelink, Barbara. Collectible Old Cookbooks with Values, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Hindley, Julia cookbook library, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - M.M. Einhorn Maxwell Books Food in America, issue 41, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Needham Book Finders Cookbooks, issue 75, [1992] (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Slotnick, Bonnie-cookbook want list, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Sunset Cookbooks-handwritten inventory, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Weindling, Barbara cookbook catalogue number 698, [2000] (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - The Wine and Food Library catalogue, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Wine books-photocopied list, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Wine books-list from Barbara L. Feret, Bookseller, [1983] (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Wine books-handwritten list, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Handwritten inventory of Brownstone's cookbook collection arranged by subject, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Unidentified handwritten inventory, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified handwritten inventory, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Subseries A: Index card file
    Contains Brownstone's bibliographical index card file.
    - Bibliographical index cards- A - Boston Public Library, undated (Box 9, Folder A)
    - Bibliographical index cards- Boston Spirited - Cross, undated (Box 9, Folder B)
    - Bibliographical index cards- Crowhurst - Foods: An Introductory, undated (Box 9, Folder C)
    - Bibliographical index cards- Foods the Indians - Hess, undated (Box 9, Folder D)
    - Bibliographical index cards-Heth - Kramer, undated (Box 10, Folder E)
    - Bibliographical index cards-Kranz - Merriman, undated (Box 10, Folder F)
    - Bibliographical index cards-Meschter - Pecan Cookbook, undated (Box 10, Folder G)
    - Bibliographical index cards-, undated (Box 10, Folder H)
    - Bibliographical index cards- Seranne - Tyson, undated (Box 10, Folder I)
- Series VIII: Menu Collection
  Brownstone's menu collection.
  - Menus, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Menus, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Menus, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Series IX: Postcard Collection
  Brownstone's postcard collection divided between marked and blank postcards.
  - Blank postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Blank postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Blank postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Blank postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Blank postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Blank postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified postcard correspondence, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified postcard correspondence, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified postcard correspondence, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Series X: Ephemera
  Ephemera arranged alphabetically by type.
  - Button-"Mild Makes It!", undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Button-"Peaces Make You Sexy!", undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Button-"Put Some Kraut in Your Life", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Button-"This Is a Grape Restaurant", undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Cards-Domino Sugar playing cards, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Medal-James Beard Foundation Award for Excellence, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 5a)
  - Medal-National Chicken Cooking Contest, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Patch-"North Carolina Pig Picker", undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Bookmark - Fanny Farmer Bookmark, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Series XI: Video recordings
  Video recordings are arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Video recordings have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Beranbaum, Rose Levy. Cookies, Cakes, and Pies, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - CGS Interview on Cable Food Network, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cuisinart-San Antonio-Food Preparation Center-Convection- Micro Oven-Mini-Mate-Scale, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Cuisinart Southwest Style, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cuisinart SuperPro Disc IV, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Cuisinart tells about food processors, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Food Processor Recipes of the American Southwest, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Freiman, Jane. The Food Processor Video Cookbook, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Great Chefs: Appetizers, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Guests Tomorrow Cook Today, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Mandel, Abby. Cuisinart Food Processor Techniques, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Mandel, Abby. Cuisinart Food Processor Techniques, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Marshall, Lydie. The Exchange, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Mooney, Marjolein. Cuisine Cooking Club Buffet, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Morash, Marian. Victory Garden Recipes, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Patent, Greg. Indulgences and Deserts, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Patent, Greg. Ten Short Programs, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Patent, Greg. Yeast Breads and Cookies, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Pápin, Jacques. The Art of Teaching, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Rosengarten, David. Taste, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Stewart, Martha. "At Home this Christmas-Lifetime Special", 1990 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Table Olives, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Series XII: Recipe Box Collection
  Series XII contains recipe boxes, published recipe index cards and non-published recipe index cards.
  Recipe boxes are arranged alphabetically according to recipe company or author.
  - Bake someone happy recipe box. Contains recipe cards from various sources., 1971, undated (Box 14, Folder data_value_missing_1c8d073079f2dc11fbcb053bd39081a5)
  - Handpainted recipe box indicating "Cecily Brownstone Recipes," (empty), undated (Box 14, Folder data_value_missing_7762736682986eb2548b2419a95f03de)
  - Campbell's Soup recipe box (empty)., undated (Box 14, Folder data_value_missing_961e71f2a62fb1bbdd0aad276bab384f)
  - Family Circle recipe box. Contains Family Circle recipe cards., 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder data_value_missing_01891be3fe2e3f5f8543262cead6a73c)
  - Unidentified, metal recipe box. Contains recipe cards by Michael Field., 1972 (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_19b38ca3e50d0d986782aa6720f321c9)
  - Land O'Lakes recipe box. Contains recipe cards from various sources., 1952, undated (Box 41, Folder data_value_missing_0a9f566abf09743e880a668ba4f418d4)
  - Nabisco Brands Inc. "Easy to Prepare" recipe box. Contains recipe cards from various sources., 1982, undated (Box 42, Folder data_value_missing_483cb1de4c23bdf4c0ab482dbced833d)
  - Quality Recipe File recipe box. Contains recipe cards by Lenore Sullivan., undated (Box 43, Folder data_value_missing_28422d76f676c1c02dfe8e30beda87a9)
  - Ragú recipe box. Contains Ragu recipe cards., undated (Box 44, Folder data_value_missing_28f67131d5e705217e34d527e1d8fb35)
  - Tested Recipe Institute recipe box. Contains recipe cards by Tested Recipe Institute., 1958 (Box 44, Folder data_value_missing_d866589fbcf0f9796afba0d95d7a71bb)